<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://pwrlab.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://pwrlab.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-23T03:07:39+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Power Transformation Lab</title><subtitle>The Power Transformation Lab at the University of California, San Diego studies the engineering and institutional requirements of deploying low-carbon energy at scale
</subtitle><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><entry><title type="html">New Reports on Southeast Asia’s Low-Carbon Energy Future</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/11/14/new-southeast-asia-energy-studies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Reports on Southeast Asia’s Low-Carbon Energy Future" /><published>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/11/14/new-southeast-asia-energy-studies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/11/14/new-southeast-asia-energy-studies.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://zenodo.org/records/17345968">Indonesia Captive Report</a></p>

<p>A system-wide analysis of how Indonesia’s industrial parks can decarbonize captive coal generation through on-site renewables, storage, and strategic grid connections aligned with national climate commitments.</p>

<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1IJeenNwuhSGLyOuSck65YCpzck9NBrho/view?usp=sharing">Vietnam Policy Brief</a></p>

<p>This policy brief evaluates how Viet Nam can meet its 2030 JETP targets and move toward a more ambitious 2035 NDC. It shows that a 47% renewable portfolio standard already delivers emissions well below the 170 Mt JETP ceiling, and that front-loading utility-scale solar plus battery storage by 2030 makes a tighter 2035 cap cheap to achieve.</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="post" /><category term="political_economy" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Indonesia Captive Report A system-wide analysis of how Indonesia’s industrial parks can decarbonize captive coal generation through on-site renewables, storage, and strategic grid connections aligned with national climate commitments. Vietnam Policy Brief This policy brief evaluates how Viet Nam can meet its 2030 JETP targets and move toward a more ambitious 2035 NDC. It shows that a 47% renewable portfolio standard already delivers emissions well below the 170 Mt JETP ceiling, and that front-loading utility-scale solar plus battery storage by 2030 makes a tighter 2035 cap cheap to achieve.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/solar_sm.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/solar_sm.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2025 Workshop on Low-Carbon Transitions in Chinese State-Owned Enterprises: Key Take-Aways</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/11/05/workshop-low-carbon-transitions-chinese-soe-takeaways.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2025 Workshop on Low-Carbon Transitions in Chinese State-Owned Enterprises: Key Take-Aways" /><published>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/11/05/workshop-low-carbon-transitions-chinese-soe-takeaways</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/11/05/workshop-low-carbon-transitions-chinese-soe-takeaways.html"><![CDATA[<p>These takeaways represent significant points made during the discussion at the ”Workshop on Low-Carbon Transitions in Chinese SOEs” held at UC San Diego on June 6-7, 2025. They are not consensus observations.</p>

<p><a href="https://china.ucsd.edu/_files/policy/21ccc-pl_2025-workshop-takeaways-soes.pdf">Link to Publication</a></p>

<p>Recommended citation:</p>

<p>21st Century China Center &amp; Power Transformation Lab. (2025). Workshop on Low-Carbon Transitions in Chinese State-Owned Enterprises: Key Take-Aways. UC San Diego. Retrieved from https://china.ucsd.edu/_files/policy/21ccc-pl_2025-workshop-takeaways-soes.pdf</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><category term="papers" /><category term="political_economy" /><category term="working_and_reports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[These takeaways represent significant points made during the discussion at the ”Workshop on Low-Carbon Transitions in Chinese SOEs” held at UC San Diego on June 6-7, 2025. They are not consensus observations. Link to Publication Recommended citation: 21st Century China Center &amp; Power Transformation Lab. (2025). Workshop on Low-Carbon Transitions in Chinese State-Owned Enterprises: Key Take-Aways. UC San Diego. Retrieved from https://china.ucsd.edu/_files/policy/21ccc-pl_2025-workshop-takeaways-soes.pdf]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/2025-workshop-soe-transitions-cover.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/2025-workshop-soe-transitions-cover.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Securing US-China Engagements on Clean Energy Technology</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/26/third-way-securing-us-clean-energy-china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securing US-China Engagements on Clean Energy Technology" /><published>2025-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/26/third-way-securing-us-clean-energy-china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/26/third-way-securing-us-clean-energy-china.html"><![CDATA[<p>Chinese technology firms—bolstered by decades of state-backed industrial policy—have become dominant global players in key clean tech sectors. Concurrently, the United States is at a pivotal moment in clean energy investment and policy, with significant public funding and regulatory efforts aimed at reshoring supply chains and advancing domestic technological leadership.</p>

<p>To scale deployment, US firms are increasingly engaging Chinese entities in a range of partnerships: as licensors, joint venture partners, technology suppliers, and US-based subsidiaries. In many of these cases, domestic firms and communities have expressed strong desires for such partnerships for their potential to accelerate US technological capabilities, attract investment, and bring manufacturing jobs to local economies.</p>

<p>However, as US-China competition intensifies amid growing global energy insecurity, managing risk while preserving strategic opportunity will be key to advancing US economic and national security objectives. One increasingly relevant (and complex) area of entanglement is Chinese firm involvement in US government supported clean energy projects.</p>

<p>This policy memo draws on new research by Professor Michael Davidson of UC San Diego, a leading China scholar whose research focuses on the engineering implications and institutional challenges of global clean energy deployment. As commissioned by Third Way, the research analyzes the structure of US-China clean energy engagements and proposes a new framework for identifying, measuring, and mitigating risks associated with these types of partnerships. The analysis identifies five categories of risk: (1) intellectual property exposure, (2) supply chain vulnerabilities, (3) facility and community security, (4) data and technology security, and (5) dual-use military concerns.</p>

<p>By applying this new framework to US-China engagements through a series of project-level case studies, we outline a dual-track policy strategy: one that minimizes risk through tighter transparency, sourcing requirements, and IP protections, and one that maximizes US advantage by enabling carefully structured collaborations that promote domestic ownership, job creation, and technological leadership.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.thirdway.org/memo/securing-us-china-engagements-on-clean-energy-technology">Policy Memo</a></p>

<p><a href="https://thirdway.imgix.net/downloads/securing-us-china-engagements-on-clean-energy-technology/securing-us-clean-energy-managing-risks-in-partnerships-with-china.pdf">Full paper</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="papers" /><category term="political_economy" /><category term="working_and_reports" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese technology firms—bolstered by decades of state-backed industrial policy—have become dominant global players in key clean tech sectors. Concurrently, the United States is at a pivotal moment in clean energy investment and policy, with significant public funding and regulatory efforts aimed at reshoring supply chains and advancing domestic technological leadership. To scale deployment, US firms are increasingly engaging Chinese entities in a range of partnerships: as licensors, joint venture partners, technology suppliers, and US-based subsidiaries. In many of these cases, domestic firms and communities have expressed strong desires for such partnerships for their potential to accelerate US technological capabilities, attract investment, and bring manufacturing jobs to local economies. However, as US-China competition intensifies amid growing global energy insecurity, managing risk while preserving strategic opportunity will be key to advancing US economic and national security objectives. One increasingly relevant (and complex) area of entanglement is Chinese firm involvement in US government supported clean energy projects. This policy memo draws on new research by Professor Michael Davidson of UC San Diego, a leading China scholar whose research focuses on the engineering implications and institutional challenges of global clean energy deployment. As commissioned by Third Way, the research analyzes the structure of US-China clean energy engagements and proposes a new framework for identifying, measuring, and mitigating risks associated with these types of partnerships. The analysis identifies five categories of risk: (1) intellectual property exposure, (2) supply chain vulnerabilities, (3) facility and community security, (4) data and technology security, and (5) dual-use military concerns. By applying this new framework to US-China engagements through a series of project-level case studies, we outline a dual-track policy strategy: one that minimizes risk through tighter transparency, sourcing requirements, and IP protections, and one that maximizes US advantage by enabling carefully structured collaborations that promote domestic ownership, job creation, and technological leadership. Policy Memo Full paper]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/solar_sm.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/solar_sm.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Key Takeaways from San Diego Workshop on Climate and U.S.-China Relations</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/23/us-china-climate-workshop-key-takeaways.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Key Takeaways from San Diego Workshop on Climate and U.S.-China Relations" /><published>2025-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/23/us-china-climate-workshop-key-takeaways</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/23/us-china-climate-workshop-key-takeaways.html"><![CDATA[<p>On May 9-10, 2025, the workshop convened leading
scholars, policy experts and practitioners to examine how the intensifying geopolitical rivalry between the U.S. and China is reshaping opportunities and barriers for collaboration on climate mitigation, technology deployment and supply chain resilience.</p>

<p>The workshop consisted of presentations in six thematic panels that centered on climate policy developments in China, the U.S., and other global economies, especially in areas of green industrial strategy, clean energy investment, data security, critical minerals and the role of subnational and academic engagement.</p>

<p>A recurring theme is that competition in green technology is here to stay, and that managing geostrategic concerns is more practical than dismissing or ignoring them. Some elements to managing this tension include clear guidelines for distinguishing national security threats from economic competition, mutual understanding surrounding the increased use of industrial policy and its impacts on global trade, and leveraging alternative channels where security or geopolitical considerations are less relevant, such as subnational governments, academia and industry.</p>

<p>The workshop also identified opportunities for targeted diplomacy, improved business environments, and proactive leadership from interested parties.</p>

<p><a href="https://china.ucsd.edu/_files/policy/2025-05_21China_Workshop-Takeaway.pdf">Takeaways</a></p>

<p>Recommended citation:</p>

<p>21CCC, Power Transformation Lab, &amp; Fudan-UC Center. (2025). Key Takeaways from San Diego Workshop on Climate and U.S.-China Relations. <em>UCSD 21st Century China Center, Power Transformation Lab, Fudan-UC Center on Contemporary China</em>. Retrieved from https://china.ucsd.edu/_files/policy/2025-05_21China_Workshop-Takeaway.pdf</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="papers" /><category term="political_economy" /><category term="working_and_reports" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[On May 9-10, 2025, the workshop convened leading scholars, policy experts and practitioners to examine how the intensifying geopolitical rivalry between the U.S. and China is reshaping opportunities and barriers for collaboration on climate mitigation, technology deployment and supply chain resilience. The workshop consisted of presentations in six thematic panels that centered on climate policy developments in China, the U.S., and other global economies, especially in areas of green industrial strategy, clean energy investment, data security, critical minerals and the role of subnational and academic engagement. A recurring theme is that competition in green technology is here to stay, and that managing geostrategic concerns is more practical than dismissing or ignoring them. Some elements to managing this tension include clear guidelines for distinguishing national security threats from economic competition, mutual understanding surrounding the increased use of industrial policy and its impacts on global trade, and leveraging alternative channels where security or geopolitical considerations are less relevant, such as subnational governments, academia and industry. The workshop also identified opportunities for targeted diplomacy, improved business environments, and proactive leadership from interested parties. Takeaways Recommended citation: 21CCC, Power Transformation Lab, &amp; Fudan-UC Center. (2025). Key Takeaways from San Diego Workshop on Climate and U.S.-China Relations. UCSD 21st Century China Center, Power Transformation Lab, Fudan-UC Center on Contemporary China. Retrieved from https://china.ucsd.edu/_files/policy/2025-05_21China_Workshop-Takeaway.pdf]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/solar_sm.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/solar_sm.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Job Opening: Postdoctoral Research Scholar: Accelerating Asia’s Decarbonization Through Trade and Investment Policies</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/20/job-postdoc-asia-trade-investment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Job Opening: Postdoctoral Research Scholar: Accelerating Asia’s Decarbonization Through Trade and Investment Policies" /><published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/20/job-postdoc-asia-trade-investment</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/20/job-postdoc-asia-trade-investment.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Power Transformation Lab (https://pwrlab.org/) at the University of California San Diego is seeking a highly motivated Postdoctoral Research Scholar to contribute to a two-year project focused on helping Southeast and South Asian countries balance trade and investment with their decarbonization goals. The successful candidate will work with a team of researchers from the UCSD School of Global Policy and Strategy and Griffith University, and with numerous civil society organizations in the region.</p>

<p>The researchers will be fully integrated into the UCSD community, which includes a highly interdisciplinary school of public policy scholars, robust campus units researching power and energy systems, and a world-class think tank studying contemporary China.</p>

<h2 id="research-focus">Research Focus</h2>

<p>The project aims to identify and promote effective trade and investment policies to accelerate decarbonization. The research will involve:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Data collection and modeling of trade, Chinese and non-Chinese investments, and localization policies in target geographies, including Indonesia, Vietnam, Thailand, Bangladesh, Pakistan, and India.</li>
  <li>Collecting and analyzing existing clean energy trade and localization policies in Southeast and South Asia.</li>
  <li>Exploring the evolution of Chinese investments and alternative investment flows in shifting global value chains (GVCs) and export opportunities.</li>
  <li>Evaluating and preparing case studies where localization policies have successfully advanced or hindered decarbonization efforts.</li>
  <li>Proposing policy and investment strategies that balance localization objectives with decarbonization goals.</li>
</ul>

<p>Qualifications</p>
<ul>
  <li>Basic qualifications (required at time of application)</li>
  <li>At the time of application candidates must either have a Ph.D. (or equivalent degree) or be ABD (all but dissertation) in economics, political science, public policy, or a related field.</li>
</ul>

<p>Additional qualifications (required at time of start)</p>
<ul>
  <li>Applicants are required to hold a Ph.D. or received a Ph.D. degree by the start of the appointment.</li>
</ul>

<p>Preferred qualifications</p>
<ul>
  <li>Background in trade policy and energy economics</li>
  <li>Prior expertise or knowledge in the regional foci (South Asia, Southeast Asia, China)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="application-requirements">Application Requirements</h2>

<p>Document requirements</p>
<ul>
  <li>Curriculum Vitae - Your most recently updated C.V.</li>
  <li>Cover Letter</li>
  <li>Statement of Research</li>
  <li>Job Market Paper (Optional)</li>
</ul>

<p>Reference requirements</p>
<ul>
  <li>3-5 required (contact information only)</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="to-apply">To Apply</h2>

<p><strong>To apply, please follow the instructions on the application link: <a href="https://apol-recruit.ucsd.edu/JPF04380">https://apol-recruit.ucsd.edu/JPF04380</a></strong></p>

<p>The University of California is an Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action Employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, national origin, disability, age or protected veteran status. Historically underrepresented groups in engineering are highly encouraged to apply.</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="post" /><category term="job" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Power Transformation Lab (https://pwrlab.org/) at the University of California San Diego is seeking a highly motivated Postdoctoral Research Scholar to contribute to a two-year project focused on helping Southeast and South Asian countries balance trade and investment with their decarbonization goals. The successful candidate will work with a team of researchers from the UCSD School of Global Policy and Strategy and Griffith University, and with numerous civil society organizations in the region. The researchers will be fully integrated into the UCSD community, which includes a highly interdisciplinary school of public policy scholars, robust campus units researching power and energy systems, and a world-class think tank studying contemporary China. Research Focus The project aims to identify and promote effective trade and investment policies to accelerate decarbonization. The research will involve: Data collection and modeling of trade, Chinese and non-Chinese investments, and localization policies in target geographies, including Indonesia, Vietnam, Thailand, Bangladesh, Pakistan, and India. Collecting and analyzing existing clean energy trade and localization policies in Southeast and South Asia. Exploring the evolution of Chinese investments and alternative investment flows in shifting global value chains (GVCs) and export opportunities. Evaluating and preparing case studies where localization policies have successfully advanced or hindered decarbonization efforts. Proposing policy and investment strategies that balance localization objectives with decarbonization goals. Qualifications Basic qualifications (required at time of application) At the time of application candidates must either have a Ph.D. (or equivalent degree) or be ABD (all but dissertation) in economics, political science, public policy, or a related field. Additional qualifications (required at time of start) Applicants are required to hold a Ph.D. or received a Ph.D. degree by the start of the appointment. Preferred qualifications Background in trade policy and energy economics Prior expertise or knowledge in the regional foci (South Asia, Southeast Asia, China) Application Requirements Document requirements Curriculum Vitae - Your most recently updated C.V. Cover Letter Statement of Research Job Market Paper (Optional) Reference requirements 3-5 required (contact information only) To Apply To apply, please follow the instructions on the application link: https://apol-recruit.ucsd.edu/JPF04380 The University of California is an Equal Opportunity/Affirmative Action Employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, national origin, disability, age or protected veteran status. Historically underrepresented groups in engineering are highly encouraged to apply.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/China_transformer.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/China_transformer.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Student Web Developers — Web Designer + Frontend/Backend (RE-Pathway Website)</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/20/job-re-pathways-web-developer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student Web Developers — Web Designer + Frontend/Backend (RE-Pathway Website)" /><published>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/20/job-re-pathways-web-developer</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/20/job-re-pathways-web-developer.html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Job Description</strong></p>

<p>The Power Transformation Lab (<a href="https://pwrlab.org/">https://pwrlab.org/</a>) at UC San Diego studies the engineering and institutional requirements of deploying low-carbon energy at scale. We work across multiple geographies and with academic, government, civil society, and industry partners to advance research and solutions to climate and environmental challenges.</p>

<p>We are hiring student developers to support the <strong>RE-Pathway Website</strong>—a <strong>cutting-edge renewable energy analysis web platform</strong> with interactive visuals, a province dashboard, and exportable tables. Open roles are listed below.</p>

<p><strong>Date Range:</strong> 11/01/2025 – 06/12/2026<br />
<strong>Hours per Week:</strong> 10–15 hours</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="position-a--undergraduate-web-designer">Position A — Undergraduate Web Designer</h2>

<h3 id="duties">Duties</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Design and manage the overall look and feel of the website hosted on WordPress.</li>
  <li>Create visually compelling layouts, themes, and templates that enhance usability and align with branding guidelines.</li>
  <li>Customize and maintain WordPress themes and plugins to deliver a polished, professional site.</li>
  <li>Coordinate with the frontend developer to integrate interactive data visuals and ensure design consistency across static and dynamic components.</li>
  <li>Ensure responsive design for mobile, tablet, and desktop platforms.</li>
  <li>Apply best practices in UX, accessibility, and SEO-friendly design.</li>
  <li>Stay updated on design trends, WordPress innovations, and web usability standards.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="qualifications">Qualifications</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Proficient in <strong>WordPress</strong> theme customization, plugin management, and content structure optimization.</li>
  <li>Strong knowledge of <strong>HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript</strong> for front-end integration and responsive design.</li>
  <li>Experience collaborating with frontend developers to ensure seamless integration of design and functionality.</li>
  <li>Familiarity with <strong>SEO best practices, accessibility (WCAG)</strong> standards, and <strong>cross-browser compatibility</strong>.</li>
  <li>Skilled in <strong>Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, XD)</strong> or <strong>Figma</strong> for mockups, wireframes, and visual design.</li>
  <li>Understanding of <strong>UI/UX principles</strong> and ability to translate user needs into visually engaging layouts.</li>
  <li>Strong eye for typography, color, layout, and visual hierarchy that align with brand identity.</li>
  <li>Ability to create <strong>modern, mobile-first</strong>, and <strong>user-friendly</strong> designs that improve engagement and usability.</li>
  <li>Demonstrated ability to balance aesthetics with technical and functional requirements.</li>
  <li>Excellent communication and collaboration skills for working with developers, content teams, and stakeholders.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>To Apply</strong></p>

<p><strong>All applications must be made following the instructions on Handshake. Applicants should use the cover letter to indicate interest in one or more of the above projects, and to describe their interests and relevant experience.</strong></p>

<p>Handshake job posting: 10410644 <a href="https://app.joinhandshake.com/job-search/10410644?query=The+Power+Transformation+Lab+%28Davidson%29&amp;per_page=25&amp;sort=relevance&amp;page=1">Handshake Application Link</a></p>

<p>Application Deadline: Oct 24th, 2025</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="position-b--undergraduate-frontendbackend-web-developers">Position B — Undergraduate Frontend/Backend Web Developers</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>When submitting a cover letter, please indicate whether you’re applying for <strong>Frontend</strong> or <strong>Backend</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="frontend-developer-duties-include">Frontend Developer duties include</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Design, develop, and maintain an intuitive and interactive search portal utilizing frontend technologies such as JS, React framework.</li>
  <li>Collaborate with backend developers and data scientists to integrate text analysis capabilities into the search portal.</li>
  <li>Convert UI/UX design wireframes into high-quality, reusable code for user-facing features, enhancing user experience and accessibility.</li>
  <li>Optimize applications for maximum speed, scalability, and user-friendliness.</li>
  <li>Implement stringent validation for all user inputs before interfacing with back-end services.</li>
  <li>Stay abreast of the latest developments in web applications and programming languages.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="qualifications-1">Qualifications</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Strong proficiency in <strong>JavaScript (ES6+), React</strong>, and modern frontend frameworks or libraries (e.g., Redux, Next.js, or TypeScript).</li>
  <li>Experience implementing <strong>responsive, accessible, and cross-browser compatible designs</strong>.</li>
  <li>Skilled in translating <strong>UI/UX wireframes</strong> into clean, maintainable, and reusable frontend components.</li>
  <li>Familiarity with <strong>RESTful APIs</strong> and <strong>JSON</strong> data structures for integrating backend and frontend systems.</li>
  <li>Understanding of <strong>frontend optimization</strong> techniques for speed, scalability, and usability.</li>
  <li>Experience with <strong>form validation, error handling</strong>, and secure user input processing.</li>
  <li>Familiarity with <strong>version control systems</strong> (e.g., Git) and modern development workflows using tools like <strong>npm, Webpack, or Vite</strong>.</li>
  <li>Proven ability to work closely with <strong>backend developers</strong> and <strong>data scientists</strong> to integrate <strong>text analytics, search functionality</strong>, or other data-driven features.</li>
  <li>Experience with <strong>API-based communication</strong> and <strong>data visualization frameworks</strong> (e.g., D3.js, Plotly, or Chart.js) is a plus.</li>
  <li>Strong appreciation of <strong>user-centered design</strong> principles and ability to improve <strong>usability, accessibility, and overall user experience</strong>.</li>
  <li>Experience collaborating with <strong>UI/UX designers</strong> to refine layout, interactivity, and visual elements.</li>
  <li>Excellent problem-solving, debugging, and analytical skills.</li>
  <li>Strong communication and teamwork abilities in interdisciplinary environments.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="backend-developer-duties-include">Backend Developer duties include</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Design, develop, and maintain scalable and robust backend services for our visuals, focusing on handling and processing search queries from the frontend.</li>
  <li>Collaborate closely with the frontend developers to understand their data requirements and ensure smooth integration of the backend with the frontend.</li>
  <li>Maintain data storage solutions, ensuring data security and integrity.</li>
  <li>Debug and resolve backend-related issues, optimizing code for performance and scalability.</li>
  <li>Stay updated on emerging technologies and architectures in the backend development space.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="qualifications-2">Qualifications</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Proficiency in one or more backend programming languages such as <strong>Python (Django, Flask, FastAPI), Node.js (Express), Java, or Go</strong>.</li>
  <li>Strong understanding of <strong>RESTful API design, data serialization (JSON), and API integration</strong> with frontend services.</li>
  <li>Experience designing and managing <strong>databases</strong> (SQL and/or NoSQL), including schema design, indexing, and performance optimization.</li>
  <li>Familiarity with <strong>data security, authentication/authorization mechanisms</strong> (OAuth, JWT), and <strong>secure data handling practices</strong>.</li>
  <li>Skilled in <strong>server optimization, query performance tuning, and caching strategies</strong> for scalability.</li>
  <li>Experience with <strong>version control (Git), CI/CD pipelines, and containerization tools</strong> (e.g., Docker, Docker Compose).</li>
  <li>Working knowledge of <strong>cloud platforms</strong> (AWS, GCP, or Azure) or container orchestration (Kubernetes) is a plus.</li>
  <li>Proven ability to work collaboratively with <strong>frontend developers</strong> and <strong>data teams</strong>, translating data requirements into performant backend logic.</li>
  <li>Strong debugging and troubleshooting skills, with experience in <strong>monitoring, logging, and profiling</strong> backend systems.</li>
  <li>Clear communication style to explain technical concepts and trade-offs across multidisciplinary teams.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>To Apply</strong></p>

<p><strong>All applications must be made following the instructions on Handshake. Applicants should use the cover letter to indicate interest in one or more of the above projects, and to describe their interests and relevant experience.</strong></p>

<p>Handshake job posting: 10401918 <a href="https://app.joinhandshake.com/job-search/10401918?query=The+Power+Transformation+Lab+%28Davidson%29&amp;per_page=25&amp;sort=relevance&amp;page=1">Handshake Application Link</a></p>

<p>Application Deadline: Oct 24th, 2025</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="post" /><category term="job" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Job Description The Power Transformation Lab (https://pwrlab.org/) at UC San Diego studies the engineering and institutional requirements of deploying low-carbon energy at scale. We work across multiple geographies and with academic, government, civil society, and industry partners to advance research and solutions to climate and environmental challenges. We are hiring student developers to support the RE-Pathway Website—a cutting-edge renewable energy analysis web platform with interactive visuals, a province dashboard, and exportable tables. Open roles are listed below. Date Range: 11/01/2025 – 06/12/2026 Hours per Week: 10–15 hours Position A — Undergraduate Web Designer Duties Design and manage the overall look and feel of the website hosted on WordPress. Create visually compelling layouts, themes, and templates that enhance usability and align with branding guidelines. Customize and maintain WordPress themes and plugins to deliver a polished, professional site. Coordinate with the frontend developer to integrate interactive data visuals and ensure design consistency across static and dynamic components. Ensure responsive design for mobile, tablet, and desktop platforms. Apply best practices in UX, accessibility, and SEO-friendly design. Stay updated on design trends, WordPress innovations, and web usability standards. Qualifications Proficient in WordPress theme customization, plugin management, and content structure optimization. Strong knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript for front-end integration and responsive design. Experience collaborating with frontend developers to ensure seamless integration of design and functionality. Familiarity with SEO best practices, accessibility (WCAG) standards, and cross-browser compatibility. Skilled in Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, XD) or Figma for mockups, wireframes, and visual design. Understanding of UI/UX principles and ability to translate user needs into visually engaging layouts. Strong eye for typography, color, layout, and visual hierarchy that align with brand identity. Ability to create modern, mobile-first, and user-friendly designs that improve engagement and usability. Demonstrated ability to balance aesthetics with technical and functional requirements. Excellent communication and collaboration skills for working with developers, content teams, and stakeholders. To Apply All applications must be made following the instructions on Handshake. Applicants should use the cover letter to indicate interest in one or more of the above projects, and to describe their interests and relevant experience. Handshake job posting: 10410644 Handshake Application Link Application Deadline: Oct 24th, 2025 Position B — Undergraduate Frontend/Backend Web Developers When submitting a cover letter, please indicate whether you’re applying for Frontend or Backend. Frontend Developer duties include Design, develop, and maintain an intuitive and interactive search portal utilizing frontend technologies such as JS, React framework. Collaborate with backend developers and data scientists to integrate text analysis capabilities into the search portal. Convert UI/UX design wireframes into high-quality, reusable code for user-facing features, enhancing user experience and accessibility. Optimize applications for maximum speed, scalability, and user-friendliness. Implement stringent validation for all user inputs before interfacing with back-end services. Stay abreast of the latest developments in web applications and programming languages. Qualifications Strong proficiency in JavaScript (ES6+), React, and modern frontend frameworks or libraries (e.g., Redux, Next.js, or TypeScript). Experience implementing responsive, accessible, and cross-browser compatible designs. Skilled in translating UI/UX wireframes into clean, maintainable, and reusable frontend components. Familiarity with RESTful APIs and JSON data structures for integrating backend and frontend systems. Understanding of frontend optimization techniques for speed, scalability, and usability. Experience with form validation, error handling, and secure user input processing. Familiarity with version control systems (e.g., Git) and modern development workflows using tools like npm, Webpack, or Vite. Proven ability to work closely with backend developers and data scientists to integrate text analytics, search functionality, or other data-driven features. Experience with API-based communication and data visualization frameworks (e.g., D3.js, Plotly, or Chart.js) is a plus. Strong appreciation of user-centered design principles and ability to improve usability, accessibility, and overall user experience. Experience collaborating with UI/UX designers to refine layout, interactivity, and visual elements. Excellent problem-solving, debugging, and analytical skills. Strong communication and teamwork abilities in interdisciplinary environments. Backend Developer duties include Design, develop, and maintain scalable and robust backend services for our visuals, focusing on handling and processing search queries from the frontend. Collaborate closely with the frontend developers to understand their data requirements and ensure smooth integration of the backend with the frontend. Maintain data storage solutions, ensuring data security and integrity. Debug and resolve backend-related issues, optimizing code for performance and scalability. Stay updated on emerging technologies and architectures in the backend development space. Qualifications Proficiency in one or more backend programming languages such as Python (Django, Flask, FastAPI), Node.js (Express), Java, or Go. Strong understanding of RESTful API design, data serialization (JSON), and API integration with frontend services. Experience designing and managing databases (SQL and/or NoSQL), including schema design, indexing, and performance optimization. Familiarity with data security, authentication/authorization mechanisms (OAuth, JWT), and secure data handling practices. Skilled in server optimization, query performance tuning, and caching strategies for scalability. Experience with version control (Git), CI/CD pipelines, and containerization tools (e.g., Docker, Docker Compose). Working knowledge of cloud platforms (AWS, GCP, or Azure) or container orchestration (Kubernetes) is a plus. Proven ability to work collaboratively with frontend developers and data teams, translating data requirements into performant backend logic. Strong debugging and troubleshooting skills, with experience in monitoring, logging, and profiling backend systems. Clear communication style to explain technical concepts and trade-offs across multidisciplinary teams. To Apply All applications must be made following the instructions on Handshake. Applicants should use the cover letter to indicate interest in one or more of the above projects, and to describe their interests and relevant experience. Handshake job posting: 10401918 Handshake Application Link Application Deadline: Oct 24th, 2025]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/hero_backgrounds/Team-small.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/hero_backgrounds/Team-small.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reaching carbon neutrality in China: Temporal and subnational limitations of renewable energy scale-up</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/17/carbon-neutrality-pathways-china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reaching carbon neutrality in China: Temporal and subnational limitations of renewable energy scale-up" /><published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/17/carbon-neutrality-pathways-china</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/10/17/carbon-neutrality-pathways-china.html"><![CDATA[<p>Acute temporal impacts and subnational limitations can hinder a country’s decarbonization pathway, despite national planning efforts. China, as the world’s largest greenhouse gas (GHG) emitter, has announced an ambitious climate policy goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2060, which will require an unprecedented scale-up of low-carbon energy technologies. China’s variable renewable energy (VRE) deployment is historically imbalanced with large geographic concentrations driven by resource endowment and institutional heterogeneities. If continued, this pattern can run into deployment limits and exacerbate challenges associated with socio-economic benefits distribution, threatening the ability to timely integrate VRE. We develop a capacity expansion model with grid operational detail and high spatial resolution to examine decadal pathways to carbon neutrality by 2060 considering localized and temporal impacts. Over these four decades, we find that all regions will increase deployment rates of renewable energy, first driven by the use of high-quality resources, and later by coal retirement and electricity demand growth. The share of provinces with high deployment pressure, where deployment requirements exceed historical rates, increases from around 45% to 100% by the final decade. If carbon capture and storage (CCS) is not available, maximum annual average deployment rates will increase by 33% and occur a decade earlier. A more stringent 1.5 °C emission target leads to more acute temporal and spatial deployment pressures in the first decade, with VRE concentrated in regions with high-quality resources and demand centers and a doubling of new transmission capacity in the first decade. Effective national and subnational policy support is necessary to coordinate VRE deployment and facilitate transitions in impacted regions.</p>

<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2025.100238">Open access</a></p>

<p>Recommended citation:</p>

<p><strong>Zhang, Z.</strong>, Zhu, Z., Gordon, J., Lu, X., Zhang, D., &amp; <strong>Davidson, M. R.</strong> (2025). Reaching carbon neutrality in China: Temporal and subnational limitations of renewable energy scale-up. <em>Advances in Applied Energy</em>, 100238. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2025.100238</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="papers" /><category term="renewable_energy_planning" /><category term="journal_article" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Acute temporal impacts and subnational limitations can hinder a country’s decarbonization pathway, despite national planning efforts. China, as the world’s largest greenhouse gas (GHG) emitter, has announced an ambitious climate policy goal of achieving carbon neutrality by 2060, which will require an unprecedented scale-up of low-carbon energy technologies. China’s variable renewable energy (VRE) deployment is historically imbalanced with large geographic concentrations driven by resource endowment and institutional heterogeneities. If continued, this pattern can run into deployment limits and exacerbate challenges associated with socio-economic benefits distribution, threatening the ability to timely integrate VRE. We develop a capacity expansion model with grid operational detail and high spatial resolution to examine decadal pathways to carbon neutrality by 2060 considering localized and temporal impacts. Over these four decades, we find that all regions will increase deployment rates of renewable energy, first driven by the use of high-quality resources, and later by coal retirement and electricity demand growth. The share of provinces with high deployment pressure, where deployment requirements exceed historical rates, increases from around 45% to 100% by the final decade. If carbon capture and storage (CCS) is not available, maximum annual average deployment rates will increase by 33% and occur a decade earlier. A more stringent 1.5 °C emission target leads to more acute temporal and spatial deployment pressures in the first decade, with VRE concentrated in regions with high-quality resources and demand centers and a doubling of new transmission capacity in the first decade. Effective national and subnational policy support is necessary to coordinate VRE deployment and facilitate transitions in impacted regions. Open access Recommended citation: Zhang, Z., Zhu, Z., Gordon, J., Lu, X., Zhang, D., &amp; Davidson, M. R. (2025). Reaching carbon neutrality in China: Temporal and subnational limitations of renewable energy scale-up. Advances in Applied Energy, 100238. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.adapen.2025.100238]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S2666792425000320-gr2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://ars.els-cdn.com/content/image/1-s2.0-S2666792425000320-gr2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Advancing Low-Carbon Industry Transition: Decarbonizing Industrial Captive Generation in Indonesia</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/30/indonesia-industry-captive-generation.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advancing Low-Carbon Industry Transition: Decarbonizing Industrial Captive Generation in Indonesia" /><published>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/30/indonesia-industry-captive-generation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/30/indonesia-industry-captive-generation.html"><![CDATA[<p>Indonesia is attempting to transition its energy system from coal while ensuring reliable and affordable electricity. The international community, for example the Just Energy Transition Partnership (JETP) and bilateral Memorandum of Understandings (MOU), have offered financial and technical support for Indonesia’s clean energy transition, but investment plans leave crucial gaps in terms of phase-out and replacement of existing captive coal power plants. These facilities contribute significantly to national greenhouse gas emissions and are
predominantly found in the metals and mining industries, sectors Indonesia is expected to grow in the future. Due to the complexity of these industrial processes and grid accessibility issues, reducing carbon emissions is also more complex than decarbonizing other sectors of the economy. Presidential Regulation 112/2022 (PerPres 112/22) has set a benchmark, committing to end new coal power plants and requiring captive industrial parks to reduce carbon emissions by 35% within 10 years of operation, although many questions remain on how these targets will be achieved.</p>

<p>Industrial park firms are interested in decarbonizing their industrial parks by exploring various available options, including energy efficiency, on-site renewable options or more commonly referred to as captive renewables, grid imports through grid connection, and others. However, they face regulatory challenges imposed by federal and state governments, a lack of direct incentives to engage in costly upgrades, unclear industry standards, and unsure financing streams. Coordinating grid connection options with Perindustrian Listrik Negara (PLN) in certain areas could be cost-effective, but these present large coordination problems among PLN’s grid and generation development, international actors, local governments, and industrial park owners and tenants.</p>

<p>This report assesses options for reducing carbon emissions in Indonesia’s captive power facilities considering plant-level options and grid upgrades, with a specific emphasis on who owns these facilities and finding viable strategies to support and implement.</p>

<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.17345968">Report</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/Power-Lab/captive-indonesia-2025">Model</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/Power-Lab/data-indonesia-2025">Data</a></p>

<p>Recommended citation:</p>

<p><strong>A Gnapathy, K.</strong>, <strong>Chen, L.</strong>, &amp; <strong>Davidson, M. R.</strong> (2025). “Advancing low-carbon industry transition: decarbonizing industrial captive generation in Indonesia.” Power Transformation Lab and School of Global Policy and Strategy, University of California San Diego, La Jolla, USA. https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.17345968</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="papers" /><category term="working_and_reports" /><category term="political_economy" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Indonesia is attempting to transition its energy system from coal while ensuring reliable and affordable electricity. The international community, for example the Just Energy Transition Partnership (JETP) and bilateral Memorandum of Understandings (MOU), have offered financial and technical support for Indonesia’s clean energy transition, but investment plans leave crucial gaps in terms of phase-out and replacement of existing captive coal power plants. These facilities contribute significantly to national greenhouse gas emissions and are predominantly found in the metals and mining industries, sectors Indonesia is expected to grow in the future. Due to the complexity of these industrial processes and grid accessibility issues, reducing carbon emissions is also more complex than decarbonizing other sectors of the economy. Presidential Regulation 112/2022 (PerPres 112/22) has set a benchmark, committing to end new coal power plants and requiring captive industrial parks to reduce carbon emissions by 35% within 10 years of operation, although many questions remain on how these targets will be achieved. Industrial park firms are interested in decarbonizing their industrial parks by exploring various available options, including energy efficiency, on-site renewable options or more commonly referred to as captive renewables, grid imports through grid connection, and others. However, they face regulatory challenges imposed by federal and state governments, a lack of direct incentives to engage in costly upgrades, unclear industry standards, and unsure financing streams. Coordinating grid connection options with Perindustrian Listrik Negara (PLN) in certain areas could be cost-effective, but these present large coordination problems among PLN’s grid and generation development, international actors, local governments, and industrial park owners and tenants. This report assesses options for reducing carbon emissions in Indonesia’s captive power facilities considering plant-level options and grid upgrades, with a specific emphasis on who owns these facilities and finding viable strategies to support and implement. Report Model Data Recommended citation: A Gnapathy, K., Chen, L., &amp; Davidson, M. R. (2025). “Advancing low-carbon industry transition: decarbonizing industrial captive generation in Indonesia.” Power Transformation Lab and School of Global Policy and Strategy, University of California San Diego, La Jolla, USA. https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.17345968]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/industrial_park.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/industrial_park.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Seeking Multiple Undergraduate Research Assistants (Fall 2025)</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/20/job-multiple-undergrad-research-assistants.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seeking Multiple Undergraduate Research Assistants (Fall 2025)" /><published>2025-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/20/job-multiple-undergrad-research-assistants</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/20/job-multiple-undergrad-research-assistants.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Power Transformation Lab at UC San Diego studies the engineering and institutional requirements of deploying low-carbon energy at scale. We work across multiple geographies and with academic, government, civil society, and industry partners to advance research and solutions to climate and environmental challenges.</p>

<p>We are hiring several undergraduate Research Assistants (RAs) to contribute across various projects. RAs will support tasks such as data collection, cleaning, analysis, visualization, and code development. Positions will be matched to student interests and skills. Please indicate preferred project or projects in your cover letter.</p>

<p>RA duties include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Implement data analysis techniques in Python/Julia for data collection and cleaning</li>
  <li>Perform basic quantitative analysis and assist with data visualization</li>
  <li>Develop project documentation and organize data sources</li>
  <li>Assist senior researchers with larger projects</li>
  <li>Collaborate with other RAs for lab development activities</li>
</ul>

<p>Projects/topics available:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Southeast Asian countries’ decarbonization</strong> - This project is analyzing decarbonization pathways for major Southeast Asian countries through the use of open datasets and analytical tools, and stakeholder engagement. The RA selected for this project will work on data collection and pre-processing to support power systems modeling projects in Southeast Asian countries.</li>
  <li><strong>China’s electricity market and open power data</strong> - This project builds open analytical tools to investigate varied market designs and policy research questions in China’s power sector, supporting existing efforts such as the Electricity Market Tracker (https://emtracker.org/). The RA selected for this project will be responsible for reviewing websites, reports and documents related to China’s power sector, collecting and processing data to support research on electricity market reform and pathways toward the country’s dual carbon goals.</li>
  <li><strong>China’s energy transition under political-economic context</strong> - This project investigates the underutilization of wind and solar power, known as curtailment, which is a persistent challenge in China’s renewable energy sector: curtailment. We analyze the technical, economic, and political drivers of this recurring issue using power system modeling and political economy analysis to identify key barriers to the country’s low-carbon transition. The RA selected for this project will work on collecting and pre-processing China’s power system data to support modeling and analytical research.</li>
  <li><strong>Database automation</strong> - This project will support various activities within the lab that rely upon consistent and easily accessible datasets. The RA selected for this project will develop automation scripts for the lab’s databases using Python and SQL, covering data extraction, transformation and loading. This project will deal with various types of data sources and may use AI tools for data collection and processing.</li>
  <li><strong>Clean Energy Customs Database</strong>  - This project investigates the impact of changes in trade and industrial policies on trade flows of clean energy and eventual deployment. The RA selected for this project will assist in building the lab’s trade customs database, including processing customs data and mapping granular customs codes across countries. This project will start with customs data from China and India and will be expanded to more countries in Asia and the U.S.</li>
  <li><strong>Western US decarbonization under socio-political context</strong> - This project will focus on incorporating socio-political factors into a power systems model for the western US. Leveraging prior work completed in the Power Transformation Lab, socio-political factors most impactful to historical solar deployment in the US have been identified. This project will focus on how to operationalize these fundings with an energy justice lens. The RA selected for this project will work on collecting and pre-processing western US power system data to support modeling and analytical research.</li>
</ul>

<p>Qualifications:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Proficient in Python or Julia, especially in:
    <ul>
      <li>Extracting/scraping data from documents and websites</li>
      <li>Data visualization</li>
      <li>Basic statistical analysis</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Interest in conducting independent research</li>
  <li>Knowledge of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) software is helpful but not required</li>
  <li>Knowledge of macro energy systems is a plus</li>
  <li>Knowledge of databases is a plus</li>
  <li>Experience with AI tools is a plus</li>
</ul>

<p>Date Range:
October 2025 - June 2026</p>

<p><strong>To Apply</strong></p>

<p><strong>All applications must be made following the instructions on Handshake. Applicants should use the cover letter to indicate interest in one or more of the above projects, and to describe their interests and relevant experience.</strong></p>

<p>Handshake job posting: 10303607
<a href="https://app.joinhandshake.com/job-search/10303607?jobType=6&amp;per_page=25&amp;page=1">Handshake Application Link</a></p>

<p><strong>Application Deadline: Oct 3rd, 2025</strong></p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="post" /><category term="job" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Power Transformation Lab at UC San Diego studies the engineering and institutional requirements of deploying low-carbon energy at scale. We work across multiple geographies and with academic, government, civil society, and industry partners to advance research and solutions to climate and environmental challenges. We are hiring several undergraduate Research Assistants (RAs) to contribute across various projects. RAs will support tasks such as data collection, cleaning, analysis, visualization, and code development. Positions will be matched to student interests and skills. Please indicate preferred project or projects in your cover letter. RA duties include: Implement data analysis techniques in Python/Julia for data collection and cleaning Perform basic quantitative analysis and assist with data visualization Develop project documentation and organize data sources Assist senior researchers with larger projects Collaborate with other RAs for lab development activities Projects/topics available: Southeast Asian countries’ decarbonization - This project is analyzing decarbonization pathways for major Southeast Asian countries through the use of open datasets and analytical tools, and stakeholder engagement. The RA selected for this project will work on data collection and pre-processing to support power systems modeling projects in Southeast Asian countries. China’s electricity market and open power data - This project builds open analytical tools to investigate varied market designs and policy research questions in China’s power sector, supporting existing efforts such as the Electricity Market Tracker (https://emtracker.org/). The RA selected for this project will be responsible for reviewing websites, reports and documents related to China’s power sector, collecting and processing data to support research on electricity market reform and pathways toward the country’s dual carbon goals. China’s energy transition under political-economic context - This project investigates the underutilization of wind and solar power, known as curtailment, which is a persistent challenge in China’s renewable energy sector: curtailment. We analyze the technical, economic, and political drivers of this recurring issue using power system modeling and political economy analysis to identify key barriers to the country’s low-carbon transition. The RA selected for this project will work on collecting and pre-processing China’s power system data to support modeling and analytical research. Database automation - This project will support various activities within the lab that rely upon consistent and easily accessible datasets. The RA selected for this project will develop automation scripts for the lab’s databases using Python and SQL, covering data extraction, transformation and loading. This project will deal with various types of data sources and may use AI tools for data collection and processing. Clean Energy Customs Database - This project investigates the impact of changes in trade and industrial policies on trade flows of clean energy and eventual deployment. The RA selected for this project will assist in building the lab’s trade customs database, including processing customs data and mapping granular customs codes across countries. This project will start with customs data from China and India and will be expanded to more countries in Asia and the U.S. Western US decarbonization under socio-political context - This project will focus on incorporating socio-political factors into a power systems model for the western US. Leveraging prior work completed in the Power Transformation Lab, socio-political factors most impactful to historical solar deployment in the US have been identified. This project will focus on how to operationalize these fundings with an energy justice lens. The RA selected for this project will work on collecting and pre-processing western US power system data to support modeling and analytical research. Qualifications: Proficient in Python or Julia, especially in: Extracting/scraping data from documents and websites Data visualization Basic statistical analysis Interest in conducting independent research Knowledge of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) software is helpful but not required Knowledge of macro energy systems is a plus Knowledge of databases is a plus Experience with AI tools is a plus Date Range: October 2025 - June 2026 To Apply All applications must be made following the instructions on Handshake. Applicants should use the cover letter to indicate interest in one or more of the above projects, and to describe their interests and relevant experience. Handshake job posting: 10303607 Handshake Application Link Application Deadline: Oct 3rd, 2025]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/hero_backgrounds/Team-small.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/hero_backgrounds/Team-small.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Critical Mineral Bottlenecks Constrain Sub-Technology Choices in Low-Carbon Energy Deployment</title><link href="https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/19/critical-mineral-bottlenecks-sub-technology.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Critical Mineral Bottlenecks Constrain Sub-Technology Choices in Low-Carbon Energy Deployment" /><published>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/19/critical-mineral-bottlenecks-sub-technology</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://pwrlab.org/2025/09/19/critical-mineral-bottlenecks-sub-technology.html"><![CDATA[<p>To meet global climate targets, countries aim to triple renewable energy capacity and rapidly deploy other low-carbon technologies by 2030. We assess the critical mineral demand required to meet these goals using a bottom-up, scenario-based approach and examine how mineral bottlenecks affect sub-technology choices. Our analysis yields three key findings. First, annual demand for critical minerals is projected to rise 6-fold, from 4.7 million tons in 2022 to 30 million tons by 2030. Second, minerals such as natural graphite, cobalt, lithium, tellurium, indium, silver, aluminum, copper, and rare earth elements may face supply constraints. Third, specific sub-technologies depend heavily on certain minerals: cadmium and tellurium shortages could limit thin-film photovoltaics; indium scarcity may hinder perovskite tandem cells; rare earths are vital for permanent-magnet wind turbines; and lithium is a key for all-solid-state batteries. Improving material efficiency and advancing mineral-efficient technologies will be essential for a resilient energy transition.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.cell.com/iscience/fulltext/S2589-0042(25)01528-7">Open access</a></p>

<p>Recommended citation:</p>

<p>Yu, D., Gu, B., Zhu, M., &amp; <strong>Davidson, M.</strong> (2025). Critical Mineral Bottlenecks Constrain Sub-Technology Choices in Low-Carbon Energy Deployment. <em>iScience</em>, 0(0). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2025.113267</p>]]></content><author><name>Power Transformation Lab</name><email>mrdavidson AT ucsd.edu</email></author><category term="papers" /><category term="renewable_energy_planning" /><category term="journal_article" /><category term="featured" /><category term="home" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To meet global climate targets, countries aim to triple renewable energy capacity and rapidly deploy other low-carbon technologies by 2030. We assess the critical mineral demand required to meet these goals using a bottom-up, scenario-based approach and examine how mineral bottlenecks affect sub-technology choices. Our analysis yields three key findings. First, annual demand for critical minerals is projected to rise 6-fold, from 4.7 million tons in 2022 to 30 million tons by 2030. Second, minerals such as natural graphite, cobalt, lithium, tellurium, indium, silver, aluminum, copper, and rare earth elements may face supply constraints. Third, specific sub-technologies depend heavily on certain minerals: cadmium and tellurium shortages could limit thin-film photovoltaics; indium scarcity may hinder perovskite tandem cells; rare earths are vital for permanent-magnet wind turbines; and lithium is a key for all-solid-state batteries. Improving material efficiency and advancing mineral-efficient technologies will be essential for a resilient energy transition. Open access Recommended citation: Yu, D., Gu, B., Zhu, M., &amp; Davidson, M. (2025). Critical Mineral Bottlenecks Constrain Sub-Technology Choices in Low-Carbon Energy Deployment. iScience, 0(0). https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2025.113267]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/mining-quarry-unsplash.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://pwrlab.org/img/mining-quarry-unsplash.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>